Tony Olagbaiye

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonyolag/ jobs@fron.io | 07944 843622

PROFILE



Born: July 1996 Nationality: Black British

Profile: A Computer Science and Maths enthusiast with experience in a variety of programming languages, platforms and development environments, and a natural passion for developing and applying knowledge.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Fluent

C • C++ • C# • Kotlin • Haskell • Rust SQL • Python2 • CSS • Shell • Go Purescript • Python3 • ŁTEX • HTML5

Competent

Java • F# • Javascript • PHP • Assembly Scheme • Typescript • OCaml

Familiar

Ruby • CLisp • Clojure Perl • Lua • Ada

LANGUAGES

Fluent

English (Native)

Competent

Japanese • Spanish

Familiar

French • Italian • Mandarin • Finnish

PLATFORMS

Fluent

Linux (inc. RHEL, Debian) • FreeBSD NetBSD • POSIX • Azure • NixOS

Competent

Windows • Android • Web

Familiar

OSX • Embedded • AWS

BIOGRAPHY

I have had reasonable experience in the Tech Sector both as a student, in industry and in freelance. As a hobbyist, I am always up to date with the latest tech, conventions, and trends, and even outside quantifiable corporate experience I have years of casual experience with almost all forms of IT, from the theoretical, to the baremetal.

EXPERIENCE

DULWICH COLLEGE | CHAIRMAN OF THE PROGRAMMING SOCIETY

Sept 2013 - Jun 2014 | London

• Tasked with running and maintaining DC ProgSoc, including leading weekly sessions teaching aspects of programming for new and experienced students.

UNIVERSITY OF YORK | FIRST AND SECOND YEAR

Sept 2014 - Jun 2016 | York

THALES UK LTD | SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

June 2016 - Jun 2017 | Manchester

 Took part in day to day running of software projects and meetings, including SCRUM meetings. Worked in Javascript/Angular JS and C++/Boost, using IBM Rhapsody and Rational Clearcase.

UNIVERSITY OF YORK | THIRD YEAR

Sept 2017 - Jun 2018 | York

MOSAIC FULFILMENT SOLUTIONS | GRADUATE DEVELOPER

Aug 2018 - Jun 2019 | Wetherby

- Took part in daily SCRUM meetings, infrastructure management and administration, full stack development and maintenance of a critical web app suite used internally and sold externally, liaising with clients and internal resources for support queries and specification, full end-to-end development of in-house data operations utilities, and most commonly SQL development and administration from the creation and maintenance of highly volatile databases containing tens of tables with millions of rows, to development of efficient and maintainable procedures and system agent jobs for data manipulation.
- Worked in Javascript/Typescript/Asp.Net-Core/Linq/SCSS, MS SQL Server 14/17, C#, using Visual Studio, VSTS/TFS, and SQL Server Management Studio.

ANSWER DIGITAL | .NET DEVELOPER

July 2019 - March 2020 | Leeds

- Functioning as a mid-tier developer. First project being an NHS team integration in Manchester, colocated 3 days a week. Working on a full stack web app for client internal use with a .Net backend, Aurelia/Typescript frontend, and a combination of SQL and MongoDB for storage (depending on security requirements). Second being a pioneer greenfield project for RPMI, replacing one side of a poor quality project completed by a previous service. The client in this case decided to colocate to us, and this used a .Net backend and JQuery/vanillaJS frontend due to requirements including use of Sitefinity as a CMS. The infrastructure was entirely Microsoft technologies, primarily Azure, and the site security (which was my primary concern) was almost entirely home grown.
- All projects function using AGILE methodologies as a top tier requirement, with daily scrum meetings, and/or whatever form of kanban is best applicable to the task. Lastly, regularly helped with the Answer Academy to train new recruits.

LOCATION EXTREME | LEAD DEVELOPER

March 2020 - March 2021 | Oxford / Remote

- · Held my position as the lead developer on the sole project developed during my tenure. Worked on the cloud component of a service for managing GPS trackers and the .Net app services based on that service. The architecure was tightly built around azure, using Azure Functions for cheap execution, Queues and CosmosDB for light data management and pipelineing, and AzureSQL for the more static data (account management). App services used ASP.Net Core with EntityFramework and NUKE for build automation with Azure DevOps. The frontends were written in ReactJS. All tests were written in F# using FsCheck for unit testing by propositional checking and Xunit for functional tests.
- Project not completed during the global issues and an ensuing company redundancy consultation due to downsizing.

FREELANCE | CONTRACTING

May 2021 - Present | Remote

• Several unspecified independent posts developing private and open source projects, during the commotion of pandemic lockdowns and for the interests of furthering ventures I believe in.

EDUCATION

DULWICH COLLEGE

Graduated Aug 2014

A-Levels

A*, A in Further Maths

2 extra unaccredited maths modules

B in Physics

C in Chemistry

GCSE

11 GCSEs

(inc. Maths, English)

of which 10 A*/A

UNIVERSITY OF YORK

COMPUTER SCIENCE WITH MATHEMATICS [GG1K]

(With a year in industry)

First Year

Theory and Practice of Programming, Computer Architecture, Mathematics of Computer Science, Core

Algebra & Calculus

Second Year

Vision and Graphics, Principles of Programming Languages, Computation and Complexity, Artificial Intelligence, Intro to Number Theory, Group Theory, Ring Theory, Linear Algebra

Third Year

Programming Correctness by Construction, Neural Computing and Applications, Information and Coding Theory, Dynamical Systems, Metric Spaces, Algebraic Number Theory, Cryptography, Topology, Galois

Theory

ACHIEVEMENTS

2016	Enlisted	Google Get Ahead Scheme
2014	1 st Round	UoY Raspberry Pi Challenge
2013	Participation	British Informatics Olympiad
2013	Silver Award	Senior Mathematics Challenge
2012	2 nd Round	Intermediate Mathematics Challenge

REFERENCES

Edward Phillips	Emma Andrews	Benjamin Johns
Mosaic Manager	Answer People Coordinator	Location Extreme Director
York House	Union Mills	Hampden House
Wetherby Road	9 Dewsbury Road	Monument Business Park
York, YO26 7NH	Leeds, LS11 5DD	Chalgrove
01904 202 140	0113 201 0600	Oxford, OX44 7RW
edward.phillips@	emma.andrews@	01865 528696
mosaic-fs.co.uk	answerdigital.co.uk	ben.johns@
		locationextreme.co.uk